Himanshu Chawla

Professional Summary

Dedicated and self-motivated to work for organizations which brings creative business solutions to its customers. I have 8+ years of experience in business development and Expansion, I trained myself to acquire the skill set that has helped me to achieve organizational goals much faster. I have been majorly in sales role in my previous organizations, I am dependable for companies in leading pilot projects and expanding in new segment or a territory. Teams which I have lead, have generated excellent results in terms of profitability. When it comes to strategy making, the management has always welcomed my suggestions. With the perseverance I was able to raise revenue by 25% in QACA with slashed cost by 20%.

Employment history

Business Partner, Bedweiser Hospitality and Travels Pvt. Ltd.. Agra, Uttar Pradesh

Oct. 2017 - Jan. 2022

Vendor management across India for managing bulk enquiries.

- Managing sales and online marketing channels for multiple hotels.
- Curating Itineraries for various travel destination.
- Resource management and maintaining SOP's.
- Bringing in various promotional schemes and ensuring sales growth.
- Making alliances and strategic partnership.
- Cost reduction by 30% for partners

Manager Business Development, Rivigo Services Pvt. Ltd.. Gurgaon, Haryana Nov. 2017 – Apr. 2018

- Led the hub of Asaf Ali road and ensured increase in new sales.
- Managed and supervised the team of executives in operations and smooth flow of documentation processing for achieving defined delivery time.
- Achieved sales revenue of 25 lakh per month on average

Manager Business Development, Quality Austria Pvt. Ltd.. Delhi, Delhi Jun. 2015 – Oct. 2017

- Liason and Alliance with MOUD (SBM, Ministry of Urban Development)& Ministry of Skill Development and Entrepreneurship, National Skill Development Corporation, Himachal Pradesh), ZED(Pan India) and Quality Council of India(QCI).
- Account management and presenting various Audit benefits to manufacturing and service oriented organizations.
- Was responsible to expand business in Nepal through channel sales

Sr. Marketing Executive, Cvent India Pvt. Ltd.. Gurgaon, Haryana

Apr. 2012 - May. 2015

- International and domestic lead generation and data refining through various methodologies defined by marketing head.
- Inside sales for geography like US and UK.
- \bullet Sales force management and data validation and timely updation.
- Was awarded as best lead researcher for the launch of Crowdcompass and Crowdtorch

Personal info

Phone:

9717739711

Email:

himanshu.nia@gmail.com

Address.

3rd Floor, Gopal Park, Chander Nagar, Delhi, 110051 (IN)

Skills

Strategy Making



Initiator



Project Management



• Collect and analyze data on customer demographics, preferences, needs, and buying habits to identify potential markets and factors affecting product demand.

Education

Amity University, Noida, Uttar Pradesh

MBA, Marketing And Sales, Apr. 2012

International Management Centre, Delhi, Delhi

BBA, Genaral Managemant, Apr. 2009